Yeah.
So in this LED,
we have all the details of all the tables,
each column description,
table table description,
everything we have, Yes, OK,
whatever the things that are highlighted
in yellow or newly like newly team was
adding here.
So this isn't sharing your screen, is it?
Yeah.
OK, now,
now you are able to see my screen, right?
Yes, yeah, yeah.
OK.
So here in the LND we have information
related to all the metadata tables, OK.
And what whatever the details that are
highlighted in LO are recently added
changes?
Yeah,
just one because seen batch or this batch
sourcing stats is the new table which I
am referring to,
but it's not added in the data model.
But this added here stores multiple
source batches information for a target
batch.
So you have all the column details and
the corresponding sample values.
OK,
once we have the information related to
all the tables,
we have the lucid flow diagram here we
have the link and if we open the link
system.
So first component here in the ABC
framework is batch preload prerequisite.
So before starting our actual zone 2
batch run,
there is a prerequisite task flow which
will which will just check zone 2 table
load will be scheduled.
So here zone 2 table load,
zone 2 table load or batch table load
will be scheduled on stone branch based
on the scheduled type.
So our zone 2 batch would be scheduled in
the schedule.
Can you can you repeat once again?
Yeah.
So here in the batch prerequisite preload
task flow before like before our batch
actual batch task flow gets triggered,
there will be a prerequisite task flow in
is ES.
This helps us to have the dependency on
zone 1 batch.
So our all our zone 2 tables are
dependent on zone 1 batch.
Zone 1 batch runs right.
So this this particular we OK stone
branch will have that OK.
So the there are two task flows which are
which would be present in the stone
branch.
One would be the batch preload
prerequisite and the second would be our
actual batch task flow.
These two are the IDFC task flows and
these two would be would have hard
dependency.
If the first one with the first task flow
gets failed the second won't be triggered.
If the first task flow gets succeeded
then only the second task flow gets you
know gets triggered or gets run OK.
The first task flow will have this
information.
It just this here we have a mapping where
it will check for the latest zone 2 batch
run batch status.
So it will check for the latest zone 2
batch run status.
If it is completed,
it will be succeeded and it will it will
invoke the actual batch task flow,
the actual zone 2 batch task flow.
If it is started or failed,
it will send out a notification stating
that the zone 2 batch latest zone 2 batch
is not yet succeeded,
is not yet completed and it will fail
this task flow once.
If this task flow gets failed,
our actual zone 2 batch task flow doesn't
get triggered.
Did you get it?
OK,
so basically we are checking if the
previous day's run is completed, correct,
Previous day's run is completed or not
that's it.
And also here this is this this batch
play requisite and these two will fall
under the zone 2,
zone 2 stone branch jobs.
What similar to these zone 2, zone 2 jobs,
we'll have jobs even for zone 1 batch
runs, right.
So the jobs which are related to zone 1
and zone 2 we have hard dependency at the
stone branch level.
If if the zone 1 stone branch job is
failed then zone 2 stone branch job won't
be triggered.
If that is completed successfully then
only this would be triggered.
This dependency of zone 1 of zone 2 on
zone 1 is kept at the stone branch
scheduling 2 level not in the ITMC table
you're getting.
So only the only if the batch and status
of zone 1 batch is either partial or
completed,
then only our zone 2 batch and get strict
you will get partial partial also.
Oh,
OK then batch this is this is the start
of our actual batch actual ABC framework.
OK, OK, batch and stress preload.
This will get the input fields.
This is not the updated one.
I'm just giving you the work through of
the previous one.
OK and here we this batch preload,
batch preload we have 5 phases OK batch
preload, job preload, job load,
job post load, batch post load.
First phase is batch preload.
This batch preload will will get these
inputs.
These will be getting these we would be
getting from a static parameter file.
OK in IDMC point of view I'm telling so
source domain,
source name domain and target all these
things are coming as a input parameters.
Based upon these values we will get the
batch ID from the batch metadata table
and using the batch ID we will get the
latest latest batch run details of this
particular batch.
So whatever the zone to batch which we
have,
we will get the details of the latest
batch, OK,
If it if the batch field status,
batch data and flag.
And similarly we'll fetch some other
details also based upon the batch data
and status,
we will set the execution type and we
will proceed further.
OK.
So here based upon the based upon these
values,
we'll fetch the batch ID from the batch
metadata table.
Using that batch ID,
we'll we'll get the latest batch run
details like status, battery run flag.
First we'll check the battery run flag if
it is equal to north.
If it is equal to north in the sense it
can be, it can be any of.
If it it, it can be new run.
If it is already N it can be new run or
restart.
It can be any of these tools.
So after after that we will check the
status.
If it is either failed or started then we
then it would be a restart scenario.
If it is completed then our current run,
current execution would be a new
execution, new run OK.
So if it is not start,
failed or started it we will it it it
execution type would be new and we a new
entry would be inserted into batch run
starts table with new execution run ID
and status equal to started OK.
If it is equal to started or failed and
batch run flag equal to end then in that
case batch run starts equal to then then
it again.
It will check for this if if it is failed
or started and batch return flag equal to
north, then the execution type is restart.
And again,
if the batch batch run stats is status is
started, then in that case,
we will update the batch run stats of the
previous record to fail.
And we will make a new entry with new
with the same execution run ID as that of
the previous with the same execution run
ID with status equal to started.
If it is failed,
we'll just make a new entry with the same
execution run ID.
In case of restart,
we'll use the same execution run IDs
previous whatever the latest runs
execution run ID would be there, right?
That would be used in case of new.
We'll use a new execution run ID.
If the batch redrun flag is not equal to
north then in that case it can be history
load catch up,
first time incremental rerun or redrun
scenario.
Redrun can be zone 1 redrun or zone 2
rerun.
If it is not N then there won't be any
changes in the batch and starts table as
entry would be already made manually
prior to the batch invocation.
In case of history catch a first time
incremental rerun scenarios,
we would be making entries into this
batch and starts table manually and how
we have to make those entries.
We have details all the details here and
then you say in this when will we add the
entry manually here.
Here we have historic historical catch up,
first time incremental Redrun,
Redrun scenario,
either John 1 Redrun or Jordan rerun In
these in these cases as part of batch
preload,
we don't do any entry as though entries
are already made into this batch run
stats table manually.
OK.
And we'll pass the execution type as T
run when the batch T run flag equal to Y.
If the batch T run flag equal to Y,
then we'll consider that as a rerun.
If it is Z,
then it represents zone 1 rerun.
If it is H histories.
If it is C, catch up.
If it is I zone,
zone to first time incremental OK these
these these are the execution types like
these these are the denotions for the
batch rerun flag values.
You can scroll it.
And So what if the batch rerun flag is N,
batch reruns automatically batch ridden
flag is automatically N.
So for any regular scenario or restart
scenario,
it will be N in case of history catch up
these or history catch up,
first time increment,
history catch up or just one time notes,
right.
So for them we are making a manual entry
and first time incremental as we as the
sourcing start dateline we are we are
depicting it right.
So for that also we are making manual
entry and rerun in case of a redrun
scenario.
Also redrun we have to give the window
for which we we we want the redrun right.
So for that purpose we are making a
manual entry.
Other than that,
in case of regular run or restart run,
the batch redrun flag would be N While we
are making any new entry automatically
the batch redrun flag would be N.
Let me summarize.
No.
So if it's a new run, fresh run,
insert a record,
I start it OK if it is a failed or if it
is already started but somewhere it is
stuck,
then we again close the previous one and
insert a new one.
Where did this batch run?
Status equal to started will be there.
Status would be started.
So in case, OK, well,
so that's an happen failed.
I understood if it has failed,
they they'll check if it has failed you
create a network issue.
In case of any network issue,
our job run would be interrupted abruptly.
Then in that case we have to trigger it
again, right?
OK.
Then in that case our batch post load job
post load won't won't happen because they
have network issues.
So in that case also you will go and
update the existing one has failed and
failed making a new entry.
If it is other things like historical
catch up,
first time incremental or reruns,
we need to insert manual record and do
this and we have to pass this execution
type values like have you told ZY
whatever.
Mostly these why we are making these
manual entries is mostly related to the
sourcing window only and also history
catch UPS for that also we are giving a
specific sourcing windows for everything,
almost everything that that would be the
reason.
One of the reasons.
There may be other reasons but that is
the main reason.
And after that whatever while we are
making that entry or if even though
whatever the entry,
the entry which is made using the
framework or the manual entry,
whatever the entry that we are using for
this particular batch run batch ID entry,
that entry will have batch ID execution
and ID execution type.
All these details will will have right.
So all these details will pass it to the
next downstream components OK and job
name,
job name will get it from the parameter
file.
This job name is nothing but the job name
which is present in the job metadata
table OK.
This value would be present in the
parameter file batch ID, execution run ID,
execution run deck and stage table.
This stage table record count is just
kept it as zero.
I'll tell you what is the significance of
stage stage table record count, OK,
based upon the input parameters,
based upon the job name and batch ID,
we will get the job ID from the job
metadata table, OK?
And we'll also check.
Is that to?
Is that to flag wherever we have?
Is that to flag, right?
We have enabled it almost everywhere.
OK, we are considering it.
OK.
So can you repeat that last table?
So wherever we have EZAC to filter,
while we are fetching any information
from the metadata tables,
we are using this EZAC to filter in the
logics EZAC because OK, EZAC,
EZAC to EZAC to just a column name in the
metadata tables.
We're using it because in some runs we
don't need like we might we,
we can deactivate the table runs which
are not required like that.
We can do OK.
So it's just active indicator.
And after that once like like a streams
stream stream stance up, right?
We have to like metadata like ID is
active or inactive for this.
If we don't want few specific table loads,
we can wait for that particular Is anyone
speaking or OK.
Yeah,
so is that is active just indicates
whether the record is active or not.
In the metadata tables of ABC we are I'm
I'm telling you explicitly that we are
considering this filter so that it would
be helpful in some scenarios where we
don't want.
So for example,
job metadata table holds the details of
the tables tables for each batch right?
So under for every batch there would be
some table details.
So all the table details would be present
in the geometric table.
So for a specific batch run,
if we don't want a few table runs then we
can deactivate that table by just marking
the is active column as N Otherwise if
any table in future got D scoped then we
can use this flag as use this column and
mark it as N so that in future batch runs
this table load won't be done.
OK got it.
Is it clear for everyone?
OK then based upon the job ID from the
job metadata table,
get the status of similar to the batch
run stats latest entry.
We would be getting the latest entry from
the job run stats OK.
After that what we would be getting the
execution type from the batch preload OK.
If the execution type equal to restart
then we'll check the latest status in the
job run stats table if it is failed or
started.
If it is failed or started then it will
go to this flow.
If it is failed then it will update the
status directly to start it here If it is
started then it will use make use of the
same record.
Use the use the existing record and we
will make an entry into job array stats
table for previous runs abrupt failure.
When we have this static status it it
would be mostly due to abrupt failure
previous run abrupt failure right?
So for that a failure we won't be able to
make an entry into job array stats.
Job array stats is kind of a log table
which will log a failure at each and
every step of the ABC framework.
I told you right?
So this kind of network failure when we
get this kind of network failure that
that related failure is not made here,
right?
So that previous runs failure details,
we are doing it here.
OK.
And then OK after that I I'll just go
with that.
So,
so basically the first above flow we are
trying to cover is for the failure
previous failure scenarios.
And the bottom part of your torch chart
is the actual new load, right.
Not, not only that, not that, huh.
Yellow part, correct.
Yeah, new read and zone 1 incremental.
Yeah, we have few other things.
First, let me go with the restart.
Yeah, I got restart, restart failure.
And if if the status is not either either
failed or started,
then we'll just skip that run.
What does it mean?
The job run for that particular job table
is already completed,
then in that case we don't need to reload
it again.
OK in case of restart after that till
here job run starts,
load is done and then for a restart load
create entries in the ETL data injection
source window table using the job.
So after job run says load,
we have ETL data injection source window
table.
So in that table we have to make entries
for each and every source table,
and they're corresponding with their
corresponding sourcing window.
I explained you Rick,
like we have to like each source table,
we have its own sourcing window.
This window would be use it for the delta
load in in a in the job load,
during our job load,
whatever the delta load that needs to be,
whatever the sourcing window that needs
to be considered,
we would be making entries here.
For that we would be using ETL metadata
table, OK.
So how we are doing it,
it would be in the logic, OK,
how we are fetching,
how we are getting the details,
how we are getting the sourcing window
for each source table that would be in
the logic.
But I'm just giving you high level here.
And after that if the source after that
like we'll prepare all these details
details here.
And after that if check if the source job
status is not equal to fail for the
current job run ID net data check OK.
So if if all the source job run statuses
are completed, then it will move forward.
Otherwise,
if any one of the job load is failed,
then in that case we will update the job
run stats status to failed and we'll send
out a notification stating that the
source job run is not completed
successfully.
That's why we are not going forward with
the target job run.
OK, target job run,
whatever the the entry that is made or
whatever,
the entry that is present here at this
step would be marked as fail here.
And while we are making any failure
status updation,
we would be making entry into the job
error status OK.
After that we will check if there are any
DQ checks assigned to assigned to this
job with is active and also we'll check
what are the we will check if there are
any active DQ checks present for this job.
If there are then in case of restart,
we'll just delete the entries that are
present in the job rule assignment table,
Job rule execution log table.
So I told you right job rule execution
log table where we would be making
entries at the job rule assignment ID
level.
So if we have two rules assigned to our
job,
there would be two entries into this
particular job rule assignment job rule
execution log table.
So whatever the entries that are made,
I'm explaining you about the restart run,
right?
Whatever the entries that are made in the
previous run would be deleted and the new
entries would be inserted into this table
with status started.
OK.
After that,
we'll do a cleanup of the target table.
After that,
we'll check the count of records that are
present in the stage table with the
current execution run ID and job run ID
and will assign that count to the stage
table record count.
OK, that's it.
So this is just a clean up of the table
and this count we would be using later.
This is the requirement from the client
in case of a restart,
if the stage load is already completed,
they don't want this stage table load
stage table load happen happen happening
in the next restart run.
OK.
That is the reason why here,
here we we are just getting the count of
the record.
OK,
now moving on to the next execution time.
So we have generic framework in place for
a rerun of for and deleting the entries
already, right.
And already in the target.
Yeah, Yeah,
we already have this table cleanup,
this one for this one, Yeah,
cleanup we have it's like it's part of
ABC's framework.
Yes.
And after that,
if the execution type is not is not equal
to restart,
then execution type would be either
history catch up or incremental renew or
rerun or Zone 1 rerun.
OK, this,
this could be the execution types.
If it is not restart, then in that case,
in all these scenarios,
we'll just make a new entry into the job
run stats table with new execution run ID,
execution run ID of the latest batch run
and the status equal to started.
Whatever the batch ID that we got right,
whatever the execution run ID from the
batch preload with using all those things
we will make an entry into the job run
stats table.
After that we have ATL data edition
source window.
So far this we have different things for
different executions.
In case of my new load using the job ID
and batch ID,
we'll just look up or in the ETL data
injection metadata table and the batch
run stretch table and we will make an
entrance into the ETL data injection
force window table.
OK.
And it it just normal thing like we'll
just get the source source table details
from the ETL data injection metadata
table.
Using the source table,
we'll just get the latest job run details
of the source and we will make entries
into it in case of rerun.
In case of rerun, just normal rerun,
normal rerun in the sense zone to read it.
In case of this rerun,
we will look up on the ETL data ingestion
source window table only to get the
details based upon the minimum execution
run ID and latest successfully executed
zone to minimum.
OK, so in case of a rerun, rerun,
what do you mean by a rerun?
Rerun is the run like it?
It's kind of a run which we are doing for
a specific period, OK,
for a specific period and here we are
getting this.
Using some execution and ID.
So if we are,
if we so the low till now till September
8, the loads happen properly.
Some failure happened today.
So because of this there is some logic
change or some functionality change.
For this reason,
we want to do a rerun from September 1st
to September 8th.
So in that case what we will do,
we will give we will provide the
execution run ID which is used for the
runs happened on September 1st in the
static parameter 5.
Using that execution run ID,
this sourcing window will be will be
framed OK.
So using that execution run ID the same
like we will check the ETL data
indication source window table.
Because for this execution run ID already
the entry would be there right on which
was made on September 1st.
So using that entry we will get the
sourcing start date OK using that would
be our sourcing start date type.
And after that sourcing end date time
would be the latest completely successful
latest complete like successfully
completed batch run,
come execution run ID using that
execution entity,
we'll bring the sourcing entity.
So this way we'll get the sourcing window
that is required for the Zone 2 rerun.
Got it.
OK, OK.
And then in case of Zone 1 rerun it is
same just same like this new run and for
the first time incremental as the
sourcing start date then we would be
giving it in the rerun John when rerun
and new run these two would be same.
It is just like normal just like regular
road for new regular and John.
When rerun it will happen normally it
will just get the source table details
and using the source table details it it
will get the source table run details,
status,
job and time and it will make entries
into the AKLA transition source window
table in case of rerun.
If it is just rerun that indicates it is
a zone to rerun OK.
If it is a zone to rerun,
it will get the execution run ID from the
static parameter file.
Using that execution run ID it will fetch
the sourcing start date time from the
same sourcing ETL data transition source
window table and also latest completed
batch run ska execution run ID.
You it will get it and like it and that,
but what when you know so sorry didn't
interfere.
So zone 1 rerun could be something like
an already completed batch.
We are rerunning in zone 1,
so we have to rerun in zone 2, right?
Correct, correct.
Yes, yes.
Therefore then already inserted data so
which we might need to clean up as well.
No, no, no,
no clean up is required in case of a zone
1 rerun.
So in case if any data got changed in the
zone 1 table,
it would be handled in the job load
itself.
So if any data got changed then it would
be updated because GRS different
timestamp would be change it for that
right?
So whatever GRS different timestamp is
nothing but the time at which the record
got arrived into the zone 1 table.
OK,
so for so for example from first to 8
whatever however they handle don't want
rerun.
We we we don't need to bother about.
But if that is happened and we got the
information how we will do is this
process.
We don't do any clean up because that is
already handled.
In case of don't when didn't happen,
their GRS defined timestamp the data
arrived into the table is also gets
changed.
So whatever the so incremental delta that
we are considering,
all the records will fall under it and
all these records would be compared
against the records are already loaded
into the target.
If there are any changes those will be
getting updated and those will fall under
the update scenario.
So we don't need to do any clean up.
If there is no change then it will be it
reject record.
Mostly reject record won't be there
because UUID column will be there for
each and every recording the German table.
So that UUID at least that UUID value
would be different.
So that value would also be updated here.
OK.
We have all the scenarios for each of
these that are already handled as part of
job load, job load design.
That's not part of zone,
that's not part of ABC.
This is how we are handling different
executions in ABC.
OK, OK, Next,
moving on to the first time incremental
load,
first time incremental load in first time
increment.
So mostly the scenarios came just because
of this sourcing window only.
So this must have incremental load.
Also we have a separate thing just
because it is having a separate like well
you know it,
it is having a some defined sourcing
start date, it's not the automatic 1.
So defined sourcing start date time which
we would be making entry into batch and
stash table.
But as per the latest changes as sourcing
start date time,
it's not present in the batch and stats
table,
it will be present in the batch sourcing
stats, right.
So we would be making entries into both
batch and stats and batch sourcing stats
OK with the status has started there and
with the sourcing start date time as per
our requirement into the batch sourcing
start date batch sourcing stats table and
using this using the batch start table.
And that whatever the value that is pass
it there would be use it here in the ETL
data initiation source window table as a
sourcing start date time and sourcing end
date time would be again it depends on
the source job run.
OK and status would also be depends on
the source job run here for first time
incremental.
Only difference between new and first
time incremental load is we are giving
this we you have to use this.
We are just informing the process to use
some specific sourcing start date time
through a manual entry.
So the process will hand will take care
of it.
It will get the sourcing start date time
from the manual entry and sourcing end
date time would be same as that of
regular.
OK and then coming to this if any same
here.
If any one of the source job runs gets
failed then it will the status in the
status in the job run stats gets updated
to fail.
And then sorry I was just just one one
check.
So if it is a first time incremental load,
we need to insert manual entry into the
source window table,
not source window table batch run stats.
Actually yes,
but the previous old old ABC framework we
just need to make manual entry only into
batch and stats table.
But now recently,
very recently in the last two weeks that
because of some additional requirement,
batch and stats table is splitted into
two tables,
batch and stats and batch sourcing stats.
OK, batch run stats,
we have details run details,
whereas batch sourcing stats will hold
the sourcing window details OK.
So that is the reason why we have to make
manual entries into the newly split batch
run stats and batch sourcing stats,
not the VTL data transition source window.
This the table that load to this table
would be handled automatically by the
framework.
OK,
next I check if the source status source
job status is not equal.
So if any one of the source job status is
failed, then in that case,
we'll just update the job run stats as
failed and we'll create an entry into the
arrow stats stating that the job run.
So one of the source job runs has failed
and there's a notice value notification.
This there ends the process.
Otherwise,
if all the source job runs are completed
successfully and we are good to move to
the next step where we'll check if there
are any job rules assigned to our job,
active job rules assigned to our job,
then we'll just make new entries into the
job rule execution log table.
And then this completes our job preload.
So we'll pass all the details, job run,
IDE stage table record, consourcing days,
whatever the whatever the information
that is required in the downstream,
we would be passing them.
OK, after that here this is the job load.
OK, this is the job load.
I'm just giving you very high level which
includes ABC integration that's it.
There may be lot of changes after this
but I'm not sure whatever the changes
recently happened.
But whatever I know I'll give you the
details once I explain this.
So here if it will check,
it will check if the staged record count
equal to 0.
If it is yes,
then it will fetch the IT will fester
record which it will fester like it will
do a load from source to stage OK if it
is.
If it is not zero,
that means the the load to stage is
already happened in the previous previous
run.
This happens only in case of a restart.
In case of a restart,
when the stage to target load failed due
to some execution error or some network
issue happened.
In that case source to stage load
happened successfully but stage 2 target
must not has not happened.
So in that case in the in the restart run,
we just it is a requirement from the
client to skip the stage table load.
So that's it here.
So we are using the full pushdown
optimization where either the loads
should be completed successfully or it
should be failed.
It would be failed,
no partial load kind of would be there in
case of full pushdown optimization.
That is the reason why we're just
directly comparing if it is 0,
if it is not zero, OK.
And here if it is is 0,
we'll directly go to the stage 2 target
table load.
If it is not,
then we'll just use the sourcing window
from the ETL retention,
ETL retention sourcing window table and
we'll fetch this information data from
the source tables.
And after that, we'll perform DQ checks,
OK and OK, I'll, I'll cover this.
So after this,
we'll just make an entry into the job run
job run stress stamp table with source
record code and target unchanged record
code.
I told you in job and stats table,
we have source record code and target
record related so many counts, right?
So for that table stats we are we are
like calculating the source record code
and target and change record code.
Here it's it.
And we are loading it into a temporary
snowflake table.
OK,
I'll I'll tell you the reason why you're
using.
Why we are using temporary table in in a
while like and after in the in parallely
we would be performing DQ checks with an
IDMC code and after that we'll check the
error CVRT code per DQ check if it is
critical check then if it is any critical
check failure.
In case of any critical check failure,
we'll route them, Pardon me, sorry.
In case of any critical check failure,
we'll route them to job related detail
timetable.
And also we, we won't load them like OK,
OK, it's OK.
I think this is not required.
Let me demo this.
In case of critical checks, we, we,
we do like this.
We'll route in,
we'll route critical error records,
critical error records into job will
execution timetable.
And we don't load the such records into
the target in this of an informational
check,
we'll route them to job will error detail
table and we'll also load them into the
target table.
OK.
After that valid in a sense the records
which are which doesn't have any DQ issue.
That means any critical critical DQ issue.
So whatever the records that are loaded
into the target would be considered for
balance reconciliation.
We'll do a aggregated sum of each and
every column and we'll we'll load them,
we'll load the source balance metrics and
do a balanced time table, OK.
And then we'll load valid RA records into
RA table and valid not R like whatever
the record.
What's whatever the records that are
valid and not RA, not unchanged records,
but we'll be loading them into the stage
table and finally from stage 2 target
would be loaded.
OK.
What is the recent change that is related
to RA is earlier RA in the sense
referential integrity?
So referential integrity,
what what do you mean by referential
integrity?
So some record is coming from the source
for which the record if we have a foreign
key in our target table.
So the record that is coming from the
source would be compared against the
parent table.
If we don't find the record in the parent
table for that particular business key or
you know the key,
the column that is used for the join,
then in that case we don't find the
foreign key.
So in that case if we don't have a
foreign,
if we don't find a record in the parent
table then we would be routing that
record into our ID RA tables RA timetable.
OK if we found the foreign key value then
only we are loading that record into the
target table.
But now even though if we don't find the
record in the parent table like the the
scenario the like the thing happening is
we are loading that record into target
table where whatever the scenario like if
we find it, if we don't find it,
we are loading it And in the next run if
we find the actual value for this
warranty we are updating it.
This is how happening as per the new
requirement.
OK, this part, this job load.
Now coming to the job post load and the
and the job poster first,
whatever the record that are loaded into
the I told you right why we are using all
the timetables here is actually APC
related tables are presented post agreed
sequel.
But our target tables are present in
Snowflake.
Full push down optimization will work
only if the source and target databases
are safe.
So in order to have their databases same,
we have created some temporary tables in
Snowflake to hold the APC related
information and we would be using those
tables in our workload.
Yeah, to actually sorry issue.
Can you go back to that job load?
I don't just one, one check,
not no questions on the DQ check or all
those things.
Maybe we'll understand once we go through
it.
Just on the first part,
it should hold right The stage table load
count that call count equal to 0.
Why were we doing that check?
So in case of restart,
the client requirement is in case of a
restart if the stage table load is
already happened in the previous run,
don't do the stage load in the current
run, current restart run.
This is the requirement from the client.
So how we are getting this is in case of
a restart,
we would be using the same execution run
ID and same job run ID as out of the
previous run.
If you observe in the job failure.
OK,
so we are checking if if the if the run
is restart,
then in that case if the stage table is
already loaded then in that case we'll
find the records in the stage table with
the same execution run ID and job run ID
already.
OK whatever.
So the whatever is done is already done.
So we can directly go and load the data
from stage to target.
If not,
we have to redo all these checks from
stage to target.
OK,
and why were we doing that load into the
temporary table that was no what data was
going to the temporary table.
I spoke out.
OK,
so here we're using few temporary tables.
First one is job run stats temporary
table.
If you remember in the job run stats
table, I showed you source record count,
target related target insert,
update record code.
I told you that these are just target
related counts.
We will check them during the code like
code walkthrough, right?
So here as parts of auditing whatever the
records that are coming from the source,
we would be calculating them as part of
this step and we would be loading them
into this Java system and also target
unchanged records because these records
are not being loaded into the target,
these are rejected records.
So we are also getting this record count.
So we are using all these record counts
and we would be doing this record count
balancing check at the end what we will,
we will do like source record count equal
to target insert record count place,
target update record count place target
reject record count place like that.
We we will do a, you know,
aggregated check against these two counts
because all the record we want to ensure
whatever the data that is coming from the
source is happened or is distributed in a
meaningful way in a correct way.
So just kind jobs run stats is on the
other date DB.
We are creating a temporary table
temporary table in Snowflake in order to
get the full push down optimization.
No, no full push down optimization in ICS.
I the the the job run status stats,
all these tables are in Arora DB, right?
Yeah, good, good.
And and the error detail timetable,
this is like job rule error detail table
is already present in the Aurora table.
And we have job rule error detail table
even in Snowflake.
If you remember job rule error detail
table,
we are we are having the information at
the record column level error correct
right?
So we won't be able to transpose the data
in the mapping itself.
First we would be loading all the data
into this table at the record level.
Later in the later error detail in the
step using SQL,
we would be transposing that single
record into multiple records based upon
the rules.
OK.
And then we have another balance
reconciliation stat stem.
So whatever the source balance metrics we
have,
we would calculate them and we are making
inserts into this balance reconciliation
timetable.
And we would be using this table to load
into actual the balance reconciliation
table later the later postal it's been
used for comparing the target values,
correct.
And this temporary table is also kind of
a temporary table.
This temp main RA table is also in
Snowflake only.
But we use this table.
It's a kind of a trunk it and load table.
So this table is common for every table
right here in order to mark the processed
already processed records it it it,
it is part of the table.
So what?
So in main RA table it has all the
information.
So if any foreign key is not present,
it's not found.
Then we'll route them to temporary and
from temporary to main array in the
second day.
On the second day,
we got the parent records.
Now whatever the records that are present
in the main array,
we use that main array table to reprocess
those records again and we will load them
into the target table.
OK, this is the whole scenario.
But now I think how they were using this,
they use the records that are loaded
yesterday into the main array table.
They use them and they will update the
value of the foreign key record with the
actual value.
OK, OK,
this things you will get gradually but
the intention here is referential
integrity concept.
I'm just stretching referential integrity
and in order to make the records
processed everything that logic wise we
need this temporary table as a
intermediate table,
OK And then so here in this like in the
second run,
whatever the records that are already
processed,
they won't come again into the temporary
table.
Then in the what does it mean?
OK, the records which are already present,
we will check main array table and
temporary table.
What whatever the records that are
present in the main array but not present
in the temp array, what does it mean?
The records are already processed.
So using that,
we will mark that record that is already
processed and in the on the third day,
then we won't calculate the processor
records, only the unprocessed ones.
We'll we'll use that.
So for that purpose, we need this.
OK, let's go over to the job.
Since we're gonna delete it from the
temporary, we,
we no temporary is kind of a trunk it and
load every time it doesn't have any
records.
OK,
we have all the data in the main array
only on the first day from temporary to
main array.
It will load on the second day whatever
the records that are present in the main
array which for which process flag is
marked as null.
So by default the process flag is null
for the records that are processed.
It would be.
Why?
OK just keep in mind and now all the
records would be null right on the second
day.
All the records would be brought from the
main array table along with the source
records.
These records would also be processed and
if they got their actual foreign key,
they would go to the target either as
insert or update.
Update is the latest change.
OK,
And now those records don't go into the
temporary.
Temporary is empty.
No,
let's say on the second all the records
got inserted into target.
No, our issue is there.
Let's assure.
So in on the in the temporary,
there are no records.
So now in this step of the job post load,
it will check the records that are
present in the temporary and main array
it it can see all the records.
There are no records for this particular
job ID.
So what does it mean?
All the records code process so it will
mark its process flag as well.
So on the third day,
no record would be present from the would
be coming from the main array like that,
OK.
After that it it will check if there are
any DQ checks assigned in the post load
in the in the this post load,
OK After the load,
if there are any DQ checks present for
this particular job, if it is CS,
then we will load the record that are
loaded into the job rule error detail
timetable to the job rule table Job load
error detail table OK After that,
if there are any records that are present,
if there are any error records in the job
rule, OK.
So job rule error detail,
I told you that record in column level
transposition happens here.
And after that once we got the records
here,
we will update if there are any records
present in the error detail table.
What does it mean?
There are some error records present,
right?
Or there are some error reports in this
particular?
So what does it mean?
There are like it,
it is failed the raw job rule assignment
which we have which we have assigned is
failed.
So that is the reason why in the job rule
execution log the status is updated to
fail and we we would be updating the
error message in the job rule execution
log which would have the record set.
The job will assignment level OK.
If it is no there are no records in the
job will error it.
It means the status like in this case we
will update the status as passed and
update the execution details.
That means no issue with any rule check.
OK, this is done.
After that it will we will check if there
are any balancing metrics assigned for a
particular job in balance reconciliation
metadata table.
If there are,
then first thing is whatever the source
balancing metrics that are present in the
balance reconciliation temp snowflake
table, we'll fetch them.
Along with that,
we we would be using some expressions
passing from the static parameter file
because this balance reconciliation
component is also a reusable 1.
So in order to calculate the target
related balancing metrics like select
clause expression would be passing it as
a parameter.
OK,
I'm just giving you at the logical
details so so that you can understand.
OK,
so we would be calculating the target
metrics as well here and then we would be
getting the out of balance value using
the source and target matrix.
If the out of balance value equal to 0,
then in that case we would be up.
We would be updating the balancing flag
and threshold flag both to Y.
If it is not,
we would be updating the balancing flag
to north and after the out of balance
well out of out of balance value would be
check that makes the threshold value.
If it is within the threshold,
then threshold threshold flag would be Y.
If it is about the threshold then update
the yeah,
if it is above the threshold then it is
updated to north.
OK.
After that we update the balance check
flag in batch OK this is done.
So using these,
all these status we would be updating,
we would be making an entry into the
balance reconciliation stacks table,
OK with all the details,
source metric value,
target metric value out of balance value
threshold flag, balance flag audit face,
whatever required using all the status
would be making it.
And then now comes to the job run stats.
So we have job run stats, right?
So there we have so many columns,
job run stats.
Let me show you that.
This is the job run stats table.
OK, this is the job run stats table.
So here we have few details which are
already inserted during the job preload
itself.
But few details would be updated in the
job post load.
For example source record count,
source record count.
We would be getting it from the job ranch
text timetable and target record count
also these two these two details we are
already insert like making insert into
the snowflake timetable from that table
we would be getting these two values.
After the target insert record count,
we would be calculating it using some
logic inside the job job postal success
component and then target update record
count Also same target error record count
is also same target error record count.
We'll have both the error record counts
like both information and critical error
record delete record count.
As of now we don't have delete scenario.
We are passing 0 to this record to this
column and record count balancing flag.
So for this,
this source record count is compared
against the aggregated sum of target
insert update unchanged RA.
I think RA is not added here.
RA is also under OK,
there are few more the the there are few
more flags.
Let me show you here.
If I have here are the values visible for
you.
So here in the job run stats we have
source record count,
source insert record count,
source update record count,
unchanged record count.
All these things would be updated if the
RA record count is also there.
Here CRA record count is string,
Critical record count informational.
The all these three are flags.
If there are no issues with the critical
rules then it would be Y.
Same goes with informational and same
goes with balance record.
Balance record Y10Y means issue and N
means no issue.
Right?
Y means no issue green flag.
Why is green flag that means all YS means
status is completed.
OK,
there are no issue with the There are no
issue related to critical rule.
There is no issue related.
There are no records which fails the
critical rule.
OK, OK, OK.
In the sense the like whenever the
threshold flag in the balance
reconciliation is Y then it would be Y
for all the metrics,
not only one single metric it it will
consider all the metrics here, OK.
And this this would get updated and after
that small thing there OK here just
balance flags and if there are no balance
metrics at all then it would be updated
to X.
Same goes with critical and informational
checks.
Also there are no critical checks or
informational checks or no job rules
assigned for a job.
It would be updated with X OK,
All the record target related information
would be updated if check if source and
OK,
this is related to record balance flag.
So I told you that source record count is
compared against the aggregated sum of
target record count, right?
So if that is that,
if that is not matching that if that is
matching then we are updating the balance
balance recalculation flag.
Sorry, record count balance flag, yes.
Why?
If it is not then we will be updating it
as N For any job I will check the status
of the record balance flag,
critical error flag,
informational check error flag boundary.
All these flags we have already we have 4
flags in the job run stats.
Using these flags would be updating the
status in the job run stats and we would
be sending out the out the notification.
There are three scenarios.
First scenario,
when the record count balancing flag
equal to north or if any threshold
critical validation check fails or if any
balancing metrics are out of threshold.
In any of these cases happens or the
final status in the job run stats would
be updated as failed and a failure
notification would be sent out OK.
And the second one is if any one of the
informational DQ check fails,
if any one of the balancing metrics are
out of balance but within threshold.
In this case,
the job status would be marked as
completed,
but a warning notification would be sent
out.
OK, And this is the success scenario.
If all the following happens,
all the following happens.
Record count balancing flag.
Why there are no critical and
informational DQ issues?
All the balancing metrics are properly
balanced.
Then in that case,
the status is updated to complete it.
And we'll send out a notification in case
if there are any failures and both 1
warnings also present then in that case a
consolidated mail of both failures and
warnings will be sent.
OK last one is batch post load.
Here it will check whether all the table
loads that falls under this batch or
completed successfully or not.
If S then it will update the status as
completed and a success not notification.
For that batch run would be sent out and
if any one of the job gets failed the the
status in the job batch run stats would
be updated to fail and I fail your
notification would be sent out.
OK, this is the architecture.
So if you want any details,
you can go through this LLD, LLD.
If, if you like,
all the details are already present in
the LLD,
whatever that are highlighted in low rate.
I'm just repeating.
These are new changes.
If you got it, that is fine.
If you're didn't get it,
Please wait until these changes are
properly reviewed and assigned off.
OK, you can raise it still to RIA.
RIA would also be there,
she'll be helping us to understand.
Otherwise,
you can ping directly in the group if you
have any doors, me or Leah,
either one of us will help.
And I just want to open the Informatica
and I'll show you where this,
all these components would be present.
You can go through it.
It would be simple only just give me a
moment.
OK,
so we have all the related components in
the DIA common folder.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
ABC here we will have all the components.
So we have job reload, task flow,
job preload failure, task flow,
job postal failure, task flow,
job postal success transfer,
all the transfer we have.
But the job,
if you want to check any job level
transfer,
you can go to any broker or contracts
issue whatever.
Let me go to account.
So whenever you start like whenever we
start any new data domain,
we have our domain specific folder inside
which will have all the folders like ABC,
stage, main.
I don't know about this.
These are related to MVP and claims.
But these three would be present.
So ABC related components should be
copied from the DIA common folder to this
folder.
Once we copied these folders,
there are few changes that needs few
update that needs to be performed.
Those details would be present in their
mail chain.
I'll give you I'll show you that mail
chain also after that stage related
components would be present here.
Main,
main related like main target related
jobs and actual job task flow or batch
task flow related details would be here.
So I'm just showing you the batch level
task flow.
OK, so batch level task flow.
He this is the batch.
We have a session tomorrow and finish it
up.
Like I, I, I won't explain this.
I'll just show you.
Just give me 5 minutes.
That's yeah, yeah, OK, Yeah, OK,
that's five.
So I don't have any information,
but we will try to understand.
Yeah, it would be, yeah.
So this is the batch level task load,
which will have batch preload and all
these are the job level task loads which
are part of this batch.
And then we have batch post load and then
our notification.
I just want and then so here,
this is the job level task load.
I'm just opening one job level task load
for you.
So this will have job preload,
job preload failure,
actual job load and job post load failure,
job post load success.
So this is target load.
And this is your post load success.
This is so once again,
sorry from the beginning.
So this this is the job level task flow.
Here we have job preload in case if any
component in this fails execution fails.
This is the job preload task flow which
will handle the failure processes like
just updating the records in the job and
start job execution log to fail and
sending and also making entry into a job
and the stats and sending out to the
notification.
All these things it will be handled and
then stage load and then if any execution,
if if this segregation gets failed,
then we have to update it,
update the status to failed, right.
So that will be handled using job post
load failure.
And then this is stage 2 target load.
If this fails,
it will jump to the step and then job
post load success.
OK,
so these while I'm showing you these two
is these two are the integrated
components,
the components which integrated ABC and
the actual job load.
These two, these two task loads,
you won't find it in the DAA format.
If you want to create any new task flow,
any job level task flow or any batch
level task flow,
you have to refer to the existing ones.
That's why I'm just showing you, OK,
if you want, that's it.
If you want in,
we have no need to create the from the
scratch, right?
We need to copy on that particular task
also, right?
Yeah,
you can copy and and you have to upgrade
them.
Yeah, you can copy and modify them.
That's why you are OK.
Yeah.
And if you want, like I told you,
one mail, right,
Let me show that's may chain.
Sorry, let me share my screen.
OK,
so this is the mail chain where where we
will give you all the details,
all the updates related to the ABC,
because ABC ABC framework is already done
to a some extent based upon some
assumptions and based upon the
requirements,
then it is completed and it is used.
It is being used by everyone.
And on top of that,
if there are any new changes coming,
we are using this mail chain to like to
inform the team OK,
Most of few would be part of this DL.
I guess everybody would also get.
So just go from the bottom,
you will understand like what are the
changes that has happened?
What needs to be taken care while doing
while updating all the syncs.
So I told you that while once you move
there for the like mappings from the
common folder to actual domain level
folder,
you have to change connection name in
these mappings.
So that's what I want to show.
And in the coming days also,
we are expecting few changes that is
related to periodic balance sheet,
translation history catch up,
incremental load.
So all these changes we would be using
this particular mail chain to inform the
team just to have a look on this.
And also RIA is having sending some
status statuses.
I,
I don't know whether you are so this job
name few details,
few changes are happened in the code
level.
So you'll get it if you go through the
code, you'll get it.
And she has also recorded all those
sessions.
And I think Benji have already shared the
the recording sling with you right in
that group chart.
Like if if team needs any help or like
any information on any specific topics or
even the development.
Also they can go through those recordings
or anywhere if they need any KP session
you can let me.
I shouldn't team any quick stills if you
have I know it is too one single day.
Anything if you want to ask question.
No.
Yeah.
Hi, Aishwarya.
Aishwarya, where can we get this flow?
See chart links I've shared.
I've shared the LLD with right.
I'll also share it with you.
So LLD has all the data model link and
lucid flow diagram link everything.
Yeah, sure.
Yeah.
Is there any anything else?
If there are no other question,
maybe we can wrap up the call.
Thank you.
Ashley,
can you share the all the documents for
and the KT sections,
both the KT sections for yeah, download.
This is like sorry.